<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Doctrines on</title><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/doctrine/</link><description>Recent content in Doctrines on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/doctrine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Doctrine/Anti-Doctrines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Doctrine/Anti-Doctrines/</guid><description>What is an &amp;ldquo;Anti-Doctrine?&amp;rdquo; # Anti-Doctrine is my term for a doctrine or teaching that is only said to be part of our shared beliefs by those who do not believe.
&amp;ldquo;anti-doctrine&amp;rdquo; then, has a double meaning because it refers to both the opposite of doctrine - something that we do not teach instead of something we do teach - and it also refers to its use by &amp;ldquo;anti-Mormons&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Doctrine/Things-Were-Sure-Of/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Doctrine/Things-Were-Sure-Of/</guid><description>When it comes to the restored gospel there are a lot of things that we call [[What is Doctrine | Doctrine]] but not everybody agrees on what is doctrine and what isn&amp;rsquo;t. That means there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of uncertainty or ambiguity, even on subjects that many of us feel are settled.
With that in mind, what are some teachings about which we feel at least somewhat certain? What are some things that can serve as a foundation for subjects of faith as well as for logical questioning and exploration of the restored gospel?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Doctrine/What-is-Doctrine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Doctrine/What-is-Doctrine/</guid><description>For the purposes of this project we need to define a few common terms. One of the most common and troublesome terms used by memebers of the restored church is &amp;ldquo;Doctrine.&amp;rdquo;
How We Define Doctrine Here # Docrine literally means &amp;ldquo;teaching.&amp;rdquo; Any current teaching of the church is therefore a &amp;ldquo;doctrine&amp;rdquo; of the church.
Implications: # Not every doctrine will be complete, up-to-date, or even true. There is no difference between policy and doctrine.</description></item></channel></rss>