<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on</title><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Anti-Doctrines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Anti-Doctrines/</guid><description>What is an &amp;ldquo;Anti-Doctrine?&amp;rdquo; # Anti-Doctrine is my term for a doctrine or teaching that is said to be part of our shared beliefs only by those who do not believe.
&amp;ldquo;anti-doctrine&amp;rdquo; then, has a double meaning because it refers to both the opposite of doctrine - something that we do not teach instead of something we do teach - and it also refers to its use by &amp;ldquo;anti-Mormons&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Doctrine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Doctrine/</guid><description>For the purposes of this project we need to define a few common terms. One of the most common and troublesome terms used by memebers of the restored church is &amp;ldquo;Doctrine.&amp;rdquo;
How We Define Doctrine Here # [!info] Docrine literally means &amp;ldquo;teaching.&amp;rdquo; Any current teaching of the church is therefore a &amp;ldquo;doctrine&amp;rdquo; of the church.
Implications: # Not every doctrine will be complete, up-to-date, or even true.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Faith-Theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Faith-Theory/</guid><description>Any attempt to explain your faith could be called your &amp;ldquo;Faith Theory.&amp;rdquo; Like all theories, them more it can explain, the better it is.
An example of a bad Faith Theory might be &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s all a lie.&amp;rdquo; You might accept this theory because it explains some problems you&amp;rsquo;ve discovered with your faith. But any good Faith Theory must be able to explain as much as possible. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s all a lie&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t explain the very real miracles that follow the believers.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Things-Were-Sure-Of/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Things-Were-Sure-Of/</guid><description>When it comes to the restored gospel there are a lot of things that we call [[Doctrine | Doctrine]] but not everybody agrees on what is doctrine and what isn&amp;rsquo;t. That means there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of uncertainty or ambiguity, even on subjects that many of us feel are settled.
With that in mind, what are some teachings about which we feel at least somewhat certain? What are some things that can serve as a foundation for subjects of faith as well as for logical questioning and exploration of the restored gospel?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Truth-Cart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://geekgreg.github.io/amethyst/Articles/Truth-Cart/</guid><description>Historian Patrick Mason created a metaphor called a &amp;ldquo;Truth Cart&amp;rdquo; which is a way of visualizing the mental and psychological space we give to things we think are true. Here&amp;rsquo;s how he puts it:
One of the problems we have in Mormonism is that we have loaded too much into the Truth Cart. And then when anything in the cart starts to rot a bit, or look unseemly upon further inspection, some have a tendency to overturn the entire cart or seek a refund for the whole lot.</description></item></channel></rss>